The Manage Returns page in Seller Central enables you to manage buyer return and replacement
requests for seller-fulfilled orders across your stores.
To get there from the main menu in Seller Central, select Manage Returns listed under Orders.
The Manage Returns page displays four main tabs for organizing return requests.
View All shows all return and replacement requests from buyers.
Pending actions lists open requests that require your attention,
such as authorizing return requests or issuing refunds.
Completed includes all completed and closed return requests.
And the Returns with A to Z claims tab shows returns with active A to Z guarantee claims.
To locate a specific return, enter the order ID, return merchandise authorization ID,
tracking ID or ASIN in the search bar.
Narrow results using the sort By, date range and marketplace filters.
Access detailed return information by selecting more information at the bottom of any return request.
This displays shipping information, order details, total order value, item details and resolution
type.
To authorize a return, select Authorize Request from the Actions column.
Under Return Merchandise Authorization, specify whether you want Amazon to generate a RMA number
or if you prefer to provide your own.
Then choose between an Amazon-provided unpaid label or your own prepaid return label.
Provide any return instructions, then press Save.
Note that if you sell in the US, you're automatically enrolled in Amazon's prepaid return labels
program,
which issues return labels on your behalf for eligible domestic returns through Amazon Buy Shipping
Services.
If you sell in the US but don't have a US domestic return address,
visit the Customer Returns for International Sales Help page for additional guidance.
If you sell in other marketplaces, you may enroll in the Amazon prepaid return labels program
from your return settings if available in your region.
Otherwise, you'll need to generate and upload those labels yourself.
For auto-authorized returns, you can select Edit Authorization to view your return address,
update customer instructions or, if available, download the return label.
To learn more about the policies related to Amazon prepaid labels,
refer to the prepaid returns for seller-fulfilled orders help page in Seller Central.
In some cases, you may be prompted to upload a prepaid return shipping label.
Select Issue Return Shipping Label to upload your label
and return shipping information, such as the shipping carrier and tracking ID.
To process a refund, select Issue Refund from the Actions tab and choose the Refund reason.
For damaged or materially different returns, you have the option to issue a restocking fee.
Select Charge Restocking Fee, grade your returned item, enter the restocking fee percentage
and upload photos of the damaged or materially different items.
Add any additional refund amounts and select Submit Refund.
Be sure to process refunds within two business days of receiving returns.
If you do not take action regarding the refund, Amazon might refund the customer on your behalf.
Finally, when no additional action is required, complete the return process by selecting Complete
from the Actions column.
Choose the completion reason and click Save.
You can also provide instant resolutions to buyers, streamline return management processing,
and reduce return shipping costs by issuing a refund or replacement and letting the buyer
keep the original product.
This process is also known as offering a returnless resolution.
To offer a returnless resolution, navigate to Edit Returns Setting at the top of the Manage
Returns page.
Select the Resolutions tab and click the Create Returnless Resolution Rule button
to set parameters on criteria like Product Category, Return Reason, Marketplace, or Price Range.
Note that if you cancel the rule, any orders placed before then will still be subject to that rule.
To offer or remove returnless resolutions for specific SKUs, go to Manage Return Templates
from the Return Settings page.
Download the Returnless Resolution template
and follow the instructions to request or remove returnless resolutions for individual products.
You can visit the Returnless Resolutions for Seller Fulfilled Returns Help page for additional
guidance.
At the top of the Manage Returns page, you will find links and resources for more detailed
information about managing seller fulfilled returns.
You can also download your returns data
through the View Reports link.
Find solutions to common questions under Return FAQs and make
changes to your return settings under Edit Returns Setting.